[
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Liberia?",
        "answer": "Monrovia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where in Egypt is the Tomb of Tutankhamen?",
        "answer": "Valley of the Kings"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what state would you find the supposed UFO site named `Area 51`?",
        "answer": "Nevada"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Peru`s capital?",
        "answer": "Lima"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country would you find St. Basil`s cathedral?",
        "answer": "Russia"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what country would you find Mount Everest?",
        "answer": "Nepal"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what country is Lake Baikal located?",
        "answer": "Russia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What lake is the world`s deepest lake?",
        "answer": "Lake Baikal"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which island is often referred to as the `Galap\u00e1gos of Australia`?",
        "answer": "Kangaroo Island"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the highest sand dune in Europe?",
        "answer": "Arcachon, France"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the world`s tallest church?",
        "answer": "Ulm, Germany"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is Great Sand Dunes National Park?",
        "answer": "Colorado"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the world`s shortest commercial runway?",
        "answer": "Saba"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the Museum of Pop Culture?",
        "answer": "Seattle, Washington"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the world`s biggest ballet school?",
        "answer": "Cuba"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was windsurfing invented?",
        "answer": "USA"
    },
    {
        "question": "What nationality is a Breton?",
        "answer": "French"
    },
    {
        "question": "What South American city does an 82 foot statue of Christ overlook?",
        "answer": "Rio de Janeiro"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the largest island in the Indian Ocean?",
        "answer": "Madagascar"
    },
    {
        "question": "Crazy Horse and Sitting Bull were born in which US state?",
        "answer": "South Dakota"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country was the first to send an object to the Moon?",
        "answer": "The Soviet Union"
    },
    {
        "question": "Equatorial Guinea gained independence from which country in 1968?",
        "answer": "Spain"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state`s way of life and culture is described as Cajun?",
        "answer": "Louisiana`s"
    },
    {
        "question": "The 1976 Summer Olympics were held in which city?",
        "answer": "Montreal"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which city is the C.N. Tower?",
        "answer": "Toronto"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which Canadian city would you find the C.N. Tower?",
        "answer": "Toronto"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following marathons do runners cross two hemispheres: London, Boston, Paris or Singapore?",
        "answer": "London -- The race passes through the Prime Meridian at Greenwich, the line of latitude which divides the Eastern and Western Hemispheres."
    },
    {
        "question": "In what country do people speak the language they call Nihongo?",
        "answer": "Japan"
    },
    {
        "question": "What artificial lake in the U.S. was created by the construction of the Glen Canyon Dam?",
        "answer": "Lake Powell"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country is the world`s most earthquake-prone country?",
        "answer": "China -- It had 157 earthquakes from 1900 to 2016. Indonesia is second with 113 earthquakes during the same period."
    },
    {
        "question": "Albion is an alternative name for which country?",
        "answer": "Britain -- It is sometimes used poetically to refer to the island, but has fallen out of common use in English."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the capital city of Samoa?",
        "answer": "Apia -- Samoa, not to be confused with American Samoa, gained its independence from New Zealand in 1962."
    },
    {
        "question": "In which city can you find the largest bazaar in the world?",
        "answer": "Istanbul -- The Grand Bazaar (Kapal\u0131 \u00c7ar\u015f\u0131), built in the 15th century, is the oldest and largest covered market in the world."
    },
    {
        "question": "From what country does geometry originate?",
        "answer": "Egypt -- Euclid, sometimes called Euclid of Alexandria, was a Greek mathematician, often referred to as the `founder of geometry.`"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the eastern-most US state capital?",
        "answer": "Augusta"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many US states are named after a president?",
        "answer": "One - Washington"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the largest country entirely within the Southern Hemisphere?",
        "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what country would you look for the Loch Ness Monster?",
        "answer": "Scotland"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city is graced with Michelangelo`s David?",
        "answer": "Florence"
    },
    {
        "question": "Corfu is part of which country?",
        "answer": "Greece"
    },
    {
        "question": "The telephone country code 82 would connect you with which country?",
        "answer": "South Korea"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is South Korea`s telephone calling code?",
        "answer": "82"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country has the calling code 82?",
        "answer": "South Korea"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Asian country has the calling code 82?",
        "answer": "South Korea"
    },
    {
        "question": "Guaro is the national spirit in what country?",
        "answer": "Colombia -- Guaro, the colloquial name for aguardiente, is Colombia`s national spirit."
    },
    {
        "question": "Where will you find a beach called Nosy Be?",
        "answer": "Madagascar -- Nosy Be means `Big Island`. About five miles off the northwestern coast, it`s the country`s top beach destination."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which U.S. city was named for a Roman hero?",
        "answer": "Lucius Quinctius Cincinnatus -- He was a Roman Soldier in the 5th century B.C. Cincinnati was originally named Losantiville."
    },
    {
        "question": "The U.S. city, Cincinnati, was originally named what?",
        "answer": "Losantiville -- Cincinnati is named after Lucius Quinctius Cincinnatus, a 5th century B.C. Roman soldier."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the world`s most populous country that drives on the left?",
        "answer": "India"
    },
    {
        "question": "What time zone is the North Pole in?",
        "answer": "None"
    }
]